Finding Aid for the Colonial Court Records Group, 1665-1787 SR.401
State Archives of North Carolina
- Civil and Criminal Action Papers, General Court, 1720-1754; SR.401.3; 401.3; CCR 179 - CCR 186.3; CCR 197; Inventories; 14.800; General Court
  - Civil Action Papers, 1720-1754, nd; SR.401.3.1; 12.800; General Court (Box General Court, Civil Action Papers, 1720-1722, Box General Court, Civil Action Papers, 1722-1723, Box General Court, Civil Action Papers, 1723, Box General Court, Civil Action Papers, 1724, Box General Court, Civil Action
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2.1, 1726; CCR 156; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1726; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3.1, 1726; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1726; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court-Civil, folder 4.1, 1726; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court-Civil, folder 4.1)
    - General Court, Civil Action Papers, The Lords Proprietors vs. Doty, Rickard and Waldron pertaining to Monies from Whaling, 1726-1727; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil Action Papers, The Lords Proprietors vs. Doty, Rickard and Waldron pertaining to Monies from Whaling)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1727; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1727; CCR 157; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1727; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1727; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.2, 1727; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1727; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil Action Papers, Jurisdictional Dispute, Gen. Ct., vs. Ct. of Vice Admiralty involving James Trotter vs. Samuel Northey, 1728; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil Action Papers, Jurisdictional Dispute, Gen. Ct., vs. Ct. of Vice Admiralty involving James Trotter vs. Samuel Northey)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1728; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1728; CCR 158; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.2, 1728; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1728; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2.1, 1728; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1728; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1729; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1729; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.2, 1729; CCR 159; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1729; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2.1, 1729; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1729; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, Jurisdictional Dispute, Gen. Ct., vs. Ct. of Vice Admrialty involving Wm. Little, Edmund Porter, Christopher Gale and David O'Sheal, 1729-1732; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, Jurisdictional Dispute, Gen. Ct., vs. Ct. of Vice Admrialty involving Wm. Little, Edmund Porter, Christopher Gale and David O'Sheal)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1730; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1730; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1730; CCR 160; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1731; CCR 161; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1731; CCR 161; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.2, 1731; CCR 161; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1731; CCR 161; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2.1, 1731; CCR 161; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1731; CCR 161; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1732; CCR 162; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1732; CCR 162; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1732; CCR 162; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2.1, 1732; CCR 162; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2.2, 1732; CCR 162; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1732; CCR 162; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1733; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1733; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.2, 1733; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1733; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1734; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1734; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1734; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1734; CCR 163; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1734; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1734; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1735; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.1, 1735; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.2, 1735; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.3, 1735; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1.4, 1735; CCR 164; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1.4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1735; CCR 165; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1735; CCR 165; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1735; CCR 165; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1735; CCR 165; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1736; CCR 165; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1736; CCR 166; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1736; CCR 166; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1736; CCR 166; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1736; CCR 167; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1736; CCR 167; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 7, 1736; CCR 167; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 7)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1737; CCR 167; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1737; CCR 167; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1737; CCR 168; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1737; CCR 168; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, Case Concerning Jurisdiction of Court of Exchequer folder 5, 1737; CCR 168; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, Case Concerning Jurisdiction of Court of Exchequer folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1737; CCR 168; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 7, 1737; CCR 168; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 7)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 8, 1737; CCR 168; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 8)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 9, 1737; CCR 169; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 9)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1738; CCR 169; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1738; CCR 169; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1738; CCR 169; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1738; CCR 170; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1738; CCR 170; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1738; CCR 170; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1739; CCR 170; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1739; CCR 171; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1739; CCR 171; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1739; CCR 171; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1739; CCR 171; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1739; CCR 171; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1740; CCR 172; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1740; CCR 172; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1740; CCR 172; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1740; CCR 172; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1740; CCR 172; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, Cases Involving Vestry, 1739-1741; CCR 173; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, Cases Involving Vestry)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1741; CCR 173; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1741; CCR 173; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1741; CCR 173; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1741; CCR 173; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1741; CCR 174; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1741; CCR 174; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1742; CCR 174; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1742; CCR 174; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1742; CCR 174; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1742; CCR 175; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1742; CCR 175; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1742; CCR 175; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1743; CCR 175; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1743; CCR 175; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1743; CCR 176; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1743; CCR 176; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1743; CCR 176; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1743; CCR 176; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1744; CCR 176; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1744; CCR 177; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1744; CCR 177; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1744; CCR 177; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1744; CCR 177; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1744; CCR 178; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 7, 1744; CCR 178; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 7)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 8, 1744; CCR 178; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 8)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 9, 1744; CCR 178; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 9)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 10, 1744; CCR 178; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 10)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1745; CCR 179; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil- folder 2, 1745; CCR 179; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil- folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1745; CCR 179; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 4, 1745; CCR 179; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 4)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 5, 1745; CCR 180; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 5)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 6, 1745; CCR 180; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 6)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 7, 1745; CCR 180; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 7)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 8, 1745; CCR 180; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 8)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 9, 1745; CCR 180; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 9)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, 1746; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 2, 1746; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 3, 1746; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 3)
    - General Court, Civil, 1747; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1748; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1749; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1750; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1751; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1752; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1753; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, 1754; CCR 181; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil)
    - General Court, Civil, folder 1, n.d. [1720-1727]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, folder 1)
    - General Court, Civil, n.d., folder 2, n.d. [1720-1727]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, n.d., folder 2)
    - General Court, Civil, n.d., n.d. [1728-1729]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, n.d.)
    - General Court, Civil, n.d., n.d. [1730-1734]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, n.d.)
    - General Court, Civil, n.d., n.d. [1735-1736]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, n.d.)
    - General Court, Civil, n.d., n.d. [1737-1739]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, n.d.)
    - General Court, Civil, n.d., n.d, [1740-1746]; CCR 182; General Court (Folder General Court, Civil, n.d.)
  - Criminal Action Papers, 1720-1754, nd; SR.401.3.2; 2.000; General Court (Box General Court, Criminal Action Papers, 1720-1726, Box General Court, Criminal Action Papers, 1727-1731, Box General Court, Criminal Action Papers, 1732-1736, Box General Court, Criminal Court Papers, 1737-1741, Box General Court, Criminal Action Papers, 1742-1749)
    This subseries is arranged chronologically by year and may contain documents belonging to the same case from different years. The years 1738-1754 will also include documents from the Court of Assizes.
    This subseries contains documents regarding criminal actions in the North Carolina colonial courts. Criminal Action Papers include cases involving assault, murder, robbery and theft, debt owed to the crown and treason against the crown and local government.
    - General Court, Criminal, 1720; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, n.d., [1720]; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal, n.d.)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1721; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1722; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1723; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1724; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1725; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1725; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1726; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1726; CCR 183; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1727; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1727; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1728; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1728; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1729; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1729; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1730; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, n.d., [1730]; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal, n.d.)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1731; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1731-1732; CCR 184; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1732; CCR 185; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1732; CCR 185; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1733; CCR 185; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1734; CCR 185; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1735; CCR 185; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1736; CCR 185; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal, 1737; CCR 186; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal)
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1738; CCR 186; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1739; CCR 186; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1740; CCR 186; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1740; CCR 186; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1741; CCR 186; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1742; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1743; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1744; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1745; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1746; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1747; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1748-1749; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
    - General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court), 1750-1754; CCR 187; General Court (Folder General Court, Criminal (includes Assize Court))
- Civil and Criminal Action Papers, Supreme Courts, 1755-1759; SR.401.4; 401.4; CCR 139 - CCR 140; CCR 188; CCR 190 - CCR 192; CCR 198; Correspondence Receipts Accounts Dockets Lists; 1.800; General Court
  This series contains documents relating to civil and criminal suits tried in the Supreme Courts of Justice within the five districts of Edenton, Edgecombe, New Bern, Salisbury, and Wilmington as well as the Courts of Oyer and Terminer and General Goal for criminal cases. Materials for both subseries include narratives of the cases by the plaintiffs and defendants, pleas, depositions, arrest warrants and attachments, summons, debt bills, recognizances, and petitions.
  - Civil Action Papers, 1755-1759; SR.401.4.1; 1.600; General Court (Box Supreme Courts, Civil Action Papers, 1755-1756, Box Supreme Courts, Civil Action Papers, 1756-1757, Box Supreme Courts, Civil Action Papers, 1757-1758, Box Supreme Courts, Civil Action Papers, 1759)
    This subseries contains documents relating to civil suits tried in the Supreme Courts of Justice within the five districts of Edenton, Edgecombe, New Bern, Salisbury, and Wilmington. Case subjects for the Civil Action Papers subseries include debt, merchandise and goods misappropriation, goods owed, plea of trespass, plea of the case, land disputes and custody.
    - Supreme Courts, Civil, folder 1, 1755; CCR 188; General Court (Folder Supreme Courts, Civil, folder 1)